Privacy Policy of **www.muscleandstrength.com**
===============================================

This Website collects some Personal Data from its Users.

Personal Data processed for the following purposes and using the following services:
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

* * ### Advertising
        
        * ### Meta ads conversion tracking (Meta pixel), Google Ads conversion tracking, Reach and Query Click
            
            Personal Data: Trackers; Usage Data
            
        * ### Meta Audience Network
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example); Usage Data
            
        * ### Google Ad Manager, Microsoft Advertising and Google AdSense
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data

    * ### Analytics
        
        * ### Google Analytics (Universal Analytics)
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data
            
        * ### Google Analytics Advertising Reporting Features
            
            Personal Data: Trackers; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example); various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
            
        * ### Google Analytics 4
            
            Personal Data: browser information; city; device information; number of Users; session statistics; Usage Data
            
        * ### Meta Events Manager and Google Analytics (Universal Analytics) with anonymized IP
            
            Personal Data: Trackers; Usage Data
            
        * ### Google Analytics Demographics and Interests reports
            
            Personal Data: Trackers; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example)

    * ### Commercial affiliation
        
        * ### CJ Affiliate
            
            Personal Data: purchase history; Trackers; Usage Data

    * ### Contacting the User
        
        * ### Contact form
            
            Personal Data: email address; first name; phone number
            
        * ### Mailing list or newsletter
            
            Personal Data: email address; first name; gender; last name; phone number

    * ### Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)
        
        * ### Google Optimize and Google Optimize 360
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data

    * ### Displaying content from external platforms
        
        * ### YouTube video widget and Instagram widget
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data
            
        * ### SoundCloud widget
            
            Personal Data: Usage Data
            
        * ### Google Fonts
            
            Personal Data: Trackers; Usage Data

    * ### Handling payments
        
        * ### PayPal
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Handling productivity related activity
        
        * ### Google Workspace
            
            Personal Data: Data communicated while using the service

    * ### Heat mapping and session recording
        
        * ### Microsoft Clarity
            
            Personal Data: Trackers

    * ### Hosting and backend infrastructure
        
        * ### DigitalOcean
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Interaction with live chat platforms
        
        * ### Zendesk Chat
            
            Personal Data: email address; first name; Usage Data

    * ### Interaction with support and feedback platforms
        
        * ### Zendesk Widget
            
            Personal Data: Tracker

    * ### Location-based interactions
        
        * ### Geolocation
            
            Personal Data: geographic position

    * ### Managing contacts and sending messages
        
        * ### dotmailer
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; email address
            
        * ### Sendgrid
            
            Personal Data: email address; first name; last name

    * ### Managing support and contact requests
        
        * ### Zendesk
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Registration and authentication provided directly by this Website
        
        * ### Direct registration
            
            Personal Data: date of birth; email address; first name; gender; last name

    * ### Remarketing and behavioral targeting
        
        * ### Facebook Custom Audience
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; email address
            
        * ### Facebook Remarketing and Google Ads Remarketing
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data

    * ### SPAM protection
        
        * ### Google reCAPTCHA
            
            Personal Data: answers to questions; clicks; keypress events; motion sensor events; mouse movements; scroll position; touch events; Trackers; Usage Data

    * ### Tag Management
        
        * ### Google Tag Manager
            
            Personal Data: Usage Data

    * ### Traffic optimization and distribution
        
        * ### Cloudflare
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

Information on opting out of interest-based advertising
-------------------------------------------------------

In addition to any opt-out feature provided by any of the services listed in this document, Users may learn more on how to generally opt out of interest-based advertising within the dedicated section of the Cookie Policy.

Further information about the processing of Personal Data
---------------------------------------------------------

* * ### Selling goods and services online
        
        The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery.  
        The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may include the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by this Website depends on the payment system used.

Contact information
-------------------

* * ### Owner and Data Controller
        
        Muscle & Strength, LLC  
        1180 First Street South  
        Columbia, SC 29209  
        USA
        
        **Owner contact email:** privacy@muscleandstrength.com

Latest update: March 07, 2024

This document has been created with the iubenda [Privacy and Cookie Policy Generator](https://www.iubenda.com/en/privacy-and-cookie-policy-generator). See also the [Terms and Conditions Generator](https://www.iubenda.com/en/terms-and-conditions-generator). [iubenda](https://www.iubenda.com/en/privacy-and-cookie-policy-generator) hosts this content and only collects [the Personal Data strictly necessary](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/65675001) for it to be provided.
